A Guide to the Papers of Eudora Ramsay Richardson, 1925-1960
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Eudora Ramsay Richardson, 1925-1960
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9766
This collection contains ca. 4800 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of Eudora Ramsay Richardson, Richmond, VA, 3 December 1971.
Scope and Content Information
Collection contains correspondence concerning Mrs. Richardson's literary career, clippings, scrapbooks, and manuscripts of many speeches, scripts, articles, short stories and novels including Little Aleck, The Influence of Men-Incurable, Lonesome Journey, and The Woman Speaker.
Her histories of the quartermaster corps are included. Very little material from her suffrage career is present.
There is correspondence with many prominent contemporary Virginia political and literary figures including John Erskine, Ellen Glasgow, Harry Flood Byrd, and John Garland Pollard.
Contents List
- Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Comments re: articles 1927-1948
  - Letters from editors 1931 - 1953
  - Comments re: Little Aleck1932 - 1934
  - C & O Women's Case 1933
  - Ladies' Home Journal- prize script 1934
  - Democratic National Campaign 1936
  - Letters re: Influence of Men 1936
  - Mary R. Beard 1937 - 1943
  - Invitations to organizations 1937 - 1945
  - Letters re: book, Roanoke
  - American Council of Learned Societies 1943
  - War Department Record 1948 - 1950
- Short Articles, Typescripts (Box 2)
  - Columbia University papers by Eudora Ramsay Richardson 1913
  - Misc. keepsakes, including letter, 1943 Nov. 14 from Ellen Glasgow 1917-1957
  - Miscellaneous typescripts [1932]
  - Guineamen of Gloucester County, Virginia 1937
  - Reviews of The Negro in Virginia 1940
  - Typescripts re: United States history ca. 1942
  - John Elliott 1953-1956
  - Co-ed vs. Traditional College for Women, "The Happiness Equation," Hollins College history, Virginia History - Flashes of Fact ca. 1962
  - Drawings of Cumberland Settlements and Fort Nashbrough, 1780
  - Janie Porter Barrett
  - World War Two - scripts
  - Confederate Government - speeches
- Articles, Speeches, Skits, etc. (Box 3)
  - History of the Quartmaster Corps by Eudora Ramsay Richardson
  - Radio skits by Eudora Ramsay Richardson
  - T.V. skits
  - Religious Tolerance in Pioneer Maryland
  - Patrick Henry
  - Memorial Day address prepared for Col. A. N. Stubblebine Jr.
  - Sermons, Speeches
  - Scrapbook containing newspaper clippings
- Newspapers and Magazine Clippings (Box 4)
  - Newspaper clippings (photocopies) 1928 - 1936
  - Virginia Guide: Publicity - Reviews 1940
  - History - World War II 1944 - 1945
  - Eudora Ramsay Richardson Suffrage - clippings
  - Influence of Men- Publicity
  - Clippings - Eudora Ramsay Richardson
  - 2 scrapbooks of newspaper clippings
- Printed Materials (Box 5-7)
  re: Quartermaster Corps
- Manuscripts
  - Margaret Brent - Gentleman (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook of articles by Eudora Ramsay Richardson (Box 8)
  - The Influence of Men - Incurable (Box 9)
  - A Pastor's Daughter (Box 9)
  - Little Aleck (Box 9)
  - Lonesome Journey (Box 10)
  - A book based on reminiscences of David Marshall Ramsay (Box 11)
  - Courage to Change (Box 11)
  - A Pastor's Daughter (Box 12)
  - The Woman Speaker - A Handbook and Study Course on Public Speaking by Eudora Ramsay Richardson (Box 12)
  - A Hundred Years of Living (Box 12)